<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jingjing Xu</title>
    <link>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jingjing Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 11:04:02 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Commonsense Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/my-project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 11:04:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/my-project-3/</guid>
      <description>Commonsense Question Answering link
Commonsense question answering aims to answer questions which require background knowledge that is not explicitly expressed in the question. The key challenge is how to obtain evidence from external knowledge and make predictions based on the evidence. Recent works either learn to generate evidence from human-annotated evidence which is expensive to collect, or extract evidence from either structured or unstructured knowledge bases which fails to take advantages of both sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pkuseg Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/my-project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 11:04:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/my-project-2/</guid>
      <description>A multi-domain Chinese word segmentation toolkit. link
Highlights The pkuseg-python toolkit has the following features:
 Supporting multi-domain Chinese word segmentation. Pkuseg-python supports multi-domain segmentation, including domains like news, web, medicine, and tourism. Users are free to choose different pre-trained models according to the domain features of the text to be segmented. If not sure the domain of the text, users are recommended to use the default model trained on mixed-domain data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JD Dialog Challenge</title>
      <link>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/my-project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 11:04:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jingjingxupku.github.io/project/my-project-1/</guid>
      <description>In October 2018, we participated in JD Dialogue Challenge (JDDC), which is a task-oriented multi-turn dialogue challenge, and won the championship in the automatic evaluation and the second place in the manual evaluation. We also won the &amp;ldquo;Excellent Tutor Award&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Architecture Innovation Award&amp;rdquo;. Participants include Ruixuan Luo, Xuancheng Ren, Junyang Lin, Jingjing Xu, Shu Liu and so on. The instructor is Xu Sun.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>